{'question': 'Who keep a wine-shop in the Quarter Saint Antoine?', 'source': '``My name is Defarge, and I keep a wine-shop in the Quarter Saint Antoine.', 'answer': 'Charles Darnay'}
{'question': 'Who felt nothing but the production of the afflicted Gabelle hopeless to entreat Citizen Defarge further?', 'source': 'Charles Darnay felt it hopeless to entreat him further, and his pride was touched besides.', 'answer': 'Charles Darnay'}
{'question': "When did the traveller's way fare towards Paris from England?", 'source': 'The traveller fared slowly on his way, who fared towards Paris from England in the autumn of the year one thousand seven hundred and ninety-two.', 'answer': 'in the autumn of the year'}
{'question': "Who follows the chief gaoler with Charles Darnay's eyes?", 'source': "``But I hope,'' said the gentleman, following the chief gaoler with his eyes, who moved across the room, ``that you are not in secret?''", 'answer': 'the gentleman'}
{'question': "Whose hand; and the apparitions vanished from Charles Darnay's sight did another iron door close under forever?", 'source': "He turned at the grated door, to render the thanks of his heart; it closed under the gaoler's hand; and the apparitions vanished from his sight forever.", 'answer': "under the gaoler's hand; and the apparitions vanished from Charles Darnay's sight"}
{'question': 'How many mounted patriots in red caps and tri-coloured cockades were the escort?', 'source': 'The escort were two mounted patriots in red caps and tri-coloured cockades, armed with national muskets and sabres, who rode one on either side of him.', 'answer': 'two mounted patriots in red caps and tri-coloured cockades'}
{'question': 'What seemed to serve as a gloomy reminder to Defarge?', 'source': "The word ``wife'' seemed to serve as a gloomy reminder to Defarge, to say with sudden impatience, ``In the name of that sharp female newly-born, and called La Guillotine, why did you come to France?''", 'answer': "the word ``wife''"}
{'question': 'What was an excited orator addressing an excited audience on in one narrow, dark, and dirty street through which a few passed?', 'source': 'In one narrow, dark, and dirty street through which they passed, an excited orator, mounted on a stool, was addressing an excited audience on the crimes against the people, of the king and the royal family.', 'answer': 'on the crimes'}
{'question': "How many patriots led Charles Darnay's tired horse?", 'source': 'He did so, and the two patriots, leading his tired horse, turned and rode away without entering the city.', 'answer': 'the two patriots'}
{'question': 'Who resorted to the Good Republican Brutus of Antiquity?', 'source': 'Sounding Mr. Cruncher, and finding him of her opinion, Miss Pross resorted to the Good Republican Brutus of Antiquity, attended by her cavalier.', 'answer': 'Miss Pross'}
{'question': 'Who was formerly in the employ of the aristocratic English government, the enemy of France and freedom?', 'source': 'Mr. Barsad, now in the employ of the republican French government, was formerly in the employ of the aristocratic English government, the enemy of France and freedom.', 'answer': 'Mr. Barsad'}
{'question': "Who led the way to Mr. Lorry's?", 'source': "They left her at the corner of the street, and Carton led the way to Mr. Lorry's, which was within a few minutes ' walk.", 'answer': 'Carton'}
{'question': 'Who supplied the link that Mr. Lorry wanted?', 'source': "As he took a chair himself, he supplied the link that Mr. Lorry wanted, by saying to him with a frown, ``Witness at that trial.''", 'answer': 'Pray'}
{'question': 'Who play my Ace, Denunciation of Mr. Barsad to the nearest Section Committee?', 'source': '``I play my Ace, Denunciation of Mr. Barsad to the nearest Section Committee.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Who is the stake Mr. Lorry have resolved to play for?', 'source': 'Now, the stake I have resolved to play for, in case of the worst, is a friend in the Conciergerie.', 'answer': 'a friend in the Conciergerie'}
{'question': 'Where did the Sheep of the prisons turn from Mr. Cruncher?', 'source': 'The Sheep of the prisons turned from him to Sydney Carton, and said, with more decision, ``It has come to a point.', 'answer': 'to Sydney Carton'}
{'question': "Who made a dab at Miss Pross's lips with his own?", 'source': "There,'' said Solomon, making a dab at Miss Pross's lips with his own.", 'answer': 'Solomon'}
{'question': 'Who turned from Mr. Cruncher to Sydney Carton?', 'source': 'The Sheep of the prisons turned from him to Sydney Carton, and said, with more decision, ``It has come to a point.', 'answer': 'the Sheep of the prisons'}
{'question': 'Who turned to the followers of the Good Republican Brutus of Antiquity?', 'source': 'As she did so, Solomon turned to the followers of the Good Republican Brutus of Antiquity, and offered a few words of explanation in the French language, which caused them all to relapse into their former places and pursuits.', 'answer': 'Solomon'}
{'question': "When did Mr. Lorry's business eye read in the speaker's face that it was loss?", 'source': "Mr. Lorry's business eye read in the speaker's face that it was loss of time to dwell upon the point.", 'answer': 'of time to dwell upon the point'}
{'question': 'Who did the Sheep of the prisons turn from to Sydney Carton?', 'source': 'The Sheep of the prisons turned from him to Sydney Carton, and said, with more decision, ``It has come to a point.', 'answer': 'from Mr. Cruncher'}
{'question': 'Who perceived the reflection on the wall to elongate?', 'source': 'Here, Mr. Lorry perceived the reflection on the wall to elongate, and Mr. Cruncher rose and stepped forward.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Lorry perceive the reflection on?', 'source': 'Here, Mr. Lorry perceived the reflection on the wall to elongate, and Mr. Cruncher rose and stepped forward.', 'answer': 'on the wall to elongate'}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Barsad see losing cards in that Sydney Carton knew nothing of?', 'source': 'Mr. Barsad saw losing cards in it that Sydney Carton knew nothing of.', 'answer': 'in this'}
{'question': 'What had Sydney Carton been lost in amazement at with Mr. Lorry?', 'source': 'Sydney Carton, who, with Mr. Lorry, had been lost in amazement at this turn of the business, here requested Mr. Cruncher to moderate and explain himself.', 'answer': 'at this turn of the business'}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Lorry perceive on the wall to elongate?', 'source': 'Here, Mr. Lorry perceived the reflection on the wall to elongate, and Mr. Cruncher rose and stepped forward.', 'answer': 'the reflection'}
{'question': "What did Mr. Lorry's business eye read in the speaker's face that it was?", 'source': "Mr. Lorry's business eye read in the speaker's face that it was loss of time to dwell upon the point.", 'answer': 'loss of time to dwell upon the point'}
{'question': 'Who always remembered with fear and trembling?', 'source': 'He always remembered with fear and trembling, that that terrible woman had knitted when he talked with her, and had looked ominously at him as her fingers moved.', 'answer': 'a woman standing staring at each other; the man with all the outward aspect of a Frenchman and a thorough Republican; the woman, evidently English'}
{'question': 'Who are a turnkey at the Conciergerie?', 'source': "You are a turnkey at the Conciergerie?''", 'answer': 'Mr. Cruncher'}
{'question': "Whose business eye read in the speaker's face that it was loss of time to dwell upon the point?", 'source': "Mr. Lorry's business eye read in the speaker's face that it was loss of time to dwell upon the point.", 'answer': "Mr. Lorry's business eye"}
{'question': 'Who was sounding Mr. Cruncher?', 'source': 'Sounding Mr. Cruncher, and finding him of her opinion, Miss Pross resorted to the Good Republican Brutus of Antiquity, attended by her cavalier.', 'answer': 'Miss Pross'}
{'question': 'Who was a spy-- witness at the Bailey?', 'source': 'You was a spy-- witness at the Bailey.', 'answer': 'an official'}
{'question': 'Whose lips did Solomon make a dab at with his own?', 'source': "There,'' said Solomon, making a dab at Miss Pross's lips with his own.", 'answer': "at Miss Pross's lips"}
{'question': "Who said, ``Mr. Cruncher tell you once for all, there is no such thing as an escape possible''?", 'source': "``I tell you once for all, there is no such thing as an escape possible,'' said the spy, firmly.", 'answer': 'the spy'}
{'question': "What did Solomon make at Miss Pross's lips with his own?", 'source': "There,'' said Solomon, making a dab at Miss Pross's lips with his own.", 'answer': 'a dab'}
{'question': "What did the speaker who struck in,'s practiced eye see Carton's negligent recklessness of?", 'source': 'His practiced eye saw it, and made the most of it.', 'answer': 'of manner'}
{'question': 'What had the estrangement between good Miss Pross! come of?', 'source': 'As if the estrangement between them had come of any culpability of hers.', 'answer': 'of any culpability of hers'}
{'question': 'What had come of any culpability of hers?', 'source': 'As if the estrangement between them had come of any culpability of hers.', 'answer': 'the estrangement between good Miss Pross!'}
{'question': 'Whose Bank by Temple Bar was an old-fashioned place?', 'source': 'It was an old-fashioned place, moreover, in the moral attribute that the partners in the House were proud of its smallness, proud of its darkness, proud of its ugliness, proud of its incommodiousness.', 'answer': "Tellson's Bank by Temple Bar"}
{'question': "What may introduce the odd circumstance connected with Mr. Cruncher's domestic economy?", 'source': "It was a very muddy boot, and may introduce the odd circumstance connected with Mr. Cruncher's domestic economy, that, whereas he often came home after banking hours with clean boots, he often got up next morning to find the same boots covered with clay.", 'answer': 'a boot'}
{'question': "When entered on Jerry's reversionary interest in the straw his father had been chewing, and cogitated?", 'source': 'Having thus given his parent God speed, young Jerry seated himself on the stool, entered on his reversionary interest in the straw his father had been chewing, and cogitated.', 'answer': 'God speed'}
{'question': 'Whose Bank by Temple Bar was very small very ugly, very incommodious?', 'source': 'It was very small, very dark, very ugly, very incommodious.', 'answer': "Tellson's Bank by Temple Bar"}
{'question': "What was Mr. Cruncher's private lodging in Hanging-sword-alley seventeen hundred and eighty?", 'source': "The scene was Mr. Cruncher's private lodging in Hanging-sword-alley, Whitefriars: the time, half-past seven of the clock on a windy March morning, Anno Domini seventeen hundred and eighty.", 'answer': 'the scene'}
{'question': "Who saw the door-keeper making Mr. Lorry's way to Mr. Lorry?", 'source': "Mr. Cruncher's attention was here diverted to the door-keeper, whom he saw making his way to Mr. Lorry, with the note in his hand.", 'answer': 'Mr. Cruncher'}
{'question': 'Whose way to Mr. Lorry did Mr. Cruncher see the door-keeper making?', 'source': "Mr. Cruncher's attention was here diverted to the door-keeper, whom he saw making his way to Mr. Lorry, with the note in his hand.", 'answer': "Mr. Lorry's way to Mr. Lorry"}
{'question': 'What allowed Mr. Jerry Cruncher to squeeze himself into court?', 'source': 'After some delay and demur, the door grudgingly turned on its hinges a very little way, and allowed Mr. Jerry Cruncher to squeeze himself into court.', 'answer': 'the door'}
{'question': "Who did Mr. Cruncher see making Mr. Lorry's way to Mr. Lorry?", 'source': "Mr. Cruncher's attention was here diverted to the door-keeper, whom he saw making his way to Mr. Lorry, with the note in his hand.", 'answer': 'the door-keeper'}
{'question': 'Who attracted the notice of Mr. Lorry and who quietly nodded and sat down again?', 'source': 'After some gruff coughing and rubbing of his chin and signing with his hand, Jerry attracted the notice of Mr. Lorry, who had stood up to look for him, and who quietly nodded and sat down again.', 'answer': 'Jerry'}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Cruncher see the door-keeper making?', 'source': "Mr. Cruncher's attention was here diverted to the door-keeper, whom he saw making his way to Mr. Lorry, with the note in his hand.", 'answer': "Mr. Lorry's way to Mr. Lorry"}
{'question': 'Who caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be issued forth?', 'source': 'Monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens and taken his chocolate, caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open, and issued forth.', 'answer': "monseigneur having eased Paris's four men of the gallows and the wheel's burdens,"}
{'question': 'Who caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open?', 'source': 'Monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens and taken his chocolate, caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open, and issued forth.', 'answer': "monseigneur having eased Paris's four men of the gallows and the wheel's burdens,"}
{'question': 'What caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be issued forth?', 'source': 'Monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens and taken his chocolate, caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open, and issued forth.', 'answer': "monseigneur having taken Paris's chocolate,"}
{'question': 'What caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open?', 'source': 'Monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens and taken his chocolate, caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open, and issued forth.', 'answer': "monseigneur having taken Paris's chocolate,"}
{'question': "Who did monseigneur having taken Paris's chocolate, cause the doors of to be issued forth?", 'source': 'Monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens and taken his chocolate, caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open, and issued forth.', 'answer': 'of the Holiest of Holiests'}
{'question': "Who did monseigneur having taken Paris's chocolate, cause the doors of to be thrown open?", 'source': 'Monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens and taken his chocolate, caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open, and issued forth.', 'answer': 'of the Holiest of Holiests'}
{'question': 'What disfigured every human creature in attendance upon Monseigneur?', 'source': 'The leprosy of unreality disfigured every human creature in attendance upon Monseigneur.', 'answer': 'the leprosy of unreality'}
{'question': "What ran: ``The earth and the fulness thereof are mine, saith Monseigneur?''", 'source': "The text of his order (altered from the original by only a pronoun, which is not much) ran: ``The earth and the fulness thereof are mine, saith Monseigneur.''", 'answer': "the text of Monseigneur's order"}
{'question': 'What did the leprosy of unreality disfigure upon Monseigneur?', 'source': 'The leprosy of unreality disfigured every human creature in attendance upon Monseigneur.', 'answer': 'every human creature in attendance'}
{'question': "Who did monseigneur having eased Paris's four men of the gallows and the wheel's burdens, cause the doors of to be thrown open?", 'source': 'Monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens and taken his chocolate, caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open, and issued forth.', 'answer': 'of the Holiest of Holiests'}
{'question': "Who did monseigneur having eased Paris's four men of the gallows and the wheel's burdens, cause the doors of to be issued forth?", 'source': 'Monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens and taken his chocolate, caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open, and issued forth.', 'answer': 'of the Holiest of Holiests'}
{'question': 'What did the woman who stood knitting look the Marquis in?', 'source': 'But the woman who stood knitting looked up steadily, and looked the Marquis in the face.', 'answer': 'in the face'}
{'question': "What did monseigneur having taken Paris's chocolate, cause to be issued forth?", 'source': 'Monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens and taken his chocolate, caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open, and issued forth.', 'answer': 'the doors of the Holiest of Holiests'}
{'question': "What did monseigneur having taken Paris's chocolate, cause to be thrown open?", 'source': 'Monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens and taken his chocolate, caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open, and issued forth.', 'answer': 'the doors of the Holiest of Holiests'}
{'question': 'Who Defarge whispered the grim reply of Monsieur Defarge closer in his ear?', 'source': 'Monsieur Defarge whispered it closer in his ear, and frowned heavily.', 'answer': 'Monsieur'}
{'question': 'What did the second of the three address?', 'source': "``It is not often,'' said the second of the three, addressing Monsieur Defarge, ``that many of these miserable beasts know the taste of wine, or of anything but black bread and death.", 'answer': "Monsieur Defarge, ``that many of these miserable beasts know the taste of wine, or of anything but black bread and death''"}
{'question': 'What had stained the ground of the narrow street in the suburb of Saint Antoine?', 'source': 'The wine was red wine, and had stained the ground of the narrow street in the suburb of Saint Antoine, in Paris, where it was spilled.', 'answer': 'the wine'}
{'question': "Who explained, ``Monsieur forgot two playing cards in the surprise of your visit''?", 'source': "``I forgot them in the surprise of your visit,'' explained Monsieur Defarge.", 'answer': 'Monsieur Defarge'}
{'question': 'How many customers pulled off their hats to Madame Defarge?', 'source': 'The three customers pulled off their hats to Madame Defarge, with three flourishes.', 'answer': 'the three customers'}
{'question': 'When every wind that blew over France shook the rags of the scarecrows in vain took no warning?', 'source': 'But, the time was not come yet; and every wind that blew over France shook the rags of the scarecrows in vain, for the birds, fine of song and feather, took no warning.', 'answer': 'the time'}
{'question': 'Who knitted with nimble fingers and steady eyebrows?', 'source': 'Madame Defarge knitted with nimble fingers and steady eyebrows, and saw nothing.', 'answer': 'Madame Defarge'}
{'question': 'What was hunger rattled its dry bones among the roasting chestnuts in the turned cylinder; Hunger shred into?', 'source': 'Hunger rattled its dry bones among the roasting chestnuts in the turned cylinder; Hunger was shred into atomics in every farthing porringer of husky chips of potato, fried with some reluctant drops of oil.', 'answer': 'into atomics in every farthing porringer of husky chips of potato'}
{'question': 'What were grim illustrations of Want?', 'source': 'The trade signs (and they were almost as many as the shops) were, all, grim illustrations of Want.', 'answer': 'the trade signs'}
{'question': 'Who growlingly repeated the words after Miss Pross?', 'source': 'Mr. Cruncher, in an access of loyalty, growlingly repeated the words after Miss Pross, like somebody at church.', 'answer': 'Mr. Cruncher'}
{'question': "Who explained himself as meaning ``Old Nick's?''", 'source': "Mr. Cruncher, with some diffidence, explained himself as meaning ``Old Nick's.''", 'answer': 'Mr. Cruncher'}
{'question': 'Who is denounced by the Citizen and Citizeness Defarge?', 'source': 'But he is denounced-- and gravely-- by the Citizen and Citizeness Defarge.', 'answer': 'the Doctor'}
{'question': 'Who was expected back presently from the Banking House?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry was expected back presently from the Banking House.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Who did Mr. Cruncher growlingly repeat the words after?', 'source': 'Mr. Cruncher, in an access of loyalty, growlingly repeated the words after Miss Pross, like somebody at church.', 'answer': 'after Miss Pross'}
{'question': 'What had Miss Pross and Mr. Cruncher discharged carrying the money; the latter for some months past?', 'source': 'For some months past, Miss Pross and Mr. Cruncher had discharged the office of purveyors; the former carrying the money; the latter, the basket.', 'answer': 'the office of purveyors; the former'}
{'question': "When were the articles of daily consumption that were wanted purchased in the Doctor's little household?", 'source': "In the Doctor's little household, as in very many others, the articles of daily consumption that were wanted were purchased every evening, in small quantities and at various small shops.", 'answer': 'every evening'}
{'question': 'What was Mr. Lorry expected back presently from?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry was expected back presently from the Banking House.', 'answer': 'from the Banking House'}
{'question': "Who hoarsely professed himself at Miss Pross's service?", 'source': "Jerry hoarsely professed himself at Miss Pross's service.", 'answer': 'Jerry'}
{'question': 'When had Miss Pross and Mr. Cruncher discharged the office of purveyors; the former carrying the money; the latter?', 'source': 'For some months past, Miss Pross and Mr. Cruncher had discharged the office of purveyors; the former carrying the money; the latter, the basket.', 'answer': 'for some months past'}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Cruncher growlingly repeat after Miss Pross?', 'source': 'Mr. Cruncher, in an access of loyalty, growlingly repeated the words after Miss Pross, like somebody at church.', 'answer': 'the words'}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Cruncher conceive the luminous idea of?', 'source': "After some cogitation, accompanied with an intent look at his patron, Mr. Cruncher conceived the luminous idea of replying, ``Agicultooral character.''", 'answer': 'of replying'}
{'question': 'Who looked at Jerry in considerable doubt and mistrust?', 'source': 'While Sydney Carton and the Sheep of the prisons were in the adjoining dark room, speaking so low that not a sound was heard, Mr. Lorry looked at Jerry in considerable doubt and mistrust.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': "What was accompanied with an intent look at Mr. Cruncher's patron?", 'source': "After some cogitation, accompanied with an intent look at his patron, Mr. Cruncher conceived the luminous idea of replying, ``Agicultooral character.''", 'answer': 'the cogitation'}
{'question': 'Where was Doctor Manette seen?', 'source': 'A great uproar took place in the court, and in the midst of it, Doctor Manette was seen, pale and trembling, standing where he had been seated.', 'answer': 'in the midst of a great uproar'}
{'question': 'Who did Mr. Lorry look at in considerable doubt and mistrust?', 'source': 'While Sydney Carton and the Sheep of the prisons were in the adjoining dark room, speaking so low that not a sound was heard, Mr. Lorry looked at Jerry in considerable doubt and mistrust.', 'answer': 'at Jerry'}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Lorry look at Jerry in?', 'source': 'While Sydney Carton and the Sheep of the prisons were in the adjoining dark room, speaking so low that not a sound was heard, Mr. Lorry looked at Jerry in considerable doubt and mistrust.', 'answer': 'in considerable doubt and mistrust'}
{'question': "When brought unhappily to Mr. Lorry's destination?", 'source': "A few minutes brought them to Mr. Lorry's destination.", 'answer': 'a few minutes'}
{'question': 'Who conceived the luminous idea of replying?', 'source': "After some cogitation, accompanied with an intent look at his patron, Mr. Cruncher conceived the luminous idea of replying, ``Agicultooral character.''", 'answer': 'Mr. Cruncher'}
{'question': "What was smoking Sydney Carton and the Sheep of the prisons's pipe at his shop-door?", 'source': 'A little wood-sawyer, having closed his shop, was smoking his pipe at his shop-door.', 'answer': 'a little wood-sawyer'}
{'question': 'Whose destination did a few minutes bring unhappily to?', 'source': "A few minutes brought them to Mr. Lorry's destination.", 'answer': "to Mr. Lorry's destination"}
{'question': 'Where could nothing worse happen if he were denounced?', 'source': "``To propose too much, would be to put this man's head under the axe, and, as he himself said, nothing worse could happen to him if he were denounced.", 'answer': 'to Sydney Carton and the Sheep of the prisons'}
{'question': 'Who warmly thanked Mr. Stryver?', 'source': 'Mr. Darnay had kissed her hand fervently and gratefully, and had turned to Mr. Stryver, whom he warmly thanked.', 'answer': 'Mr. Darnay'}
{'question': 'Who wished Mr. Carton good night?', 'source': 'The bill being paid, Charles Darnay rose and wished him good night.', 'answer': 'Charles Darnay'}
{'question': 'Who had turned to Mr. Stryver?', 'source': 'Mr. Darnay had kissed her hand fervently and gratefully, and had turned to Mr. Stryver, whom he warmly thanked.', 'answer': 'Mr. Darnay'}
{'question': "What had made any acknowledgment of Mr. Carton's part in the day's proceedings?", 'source': "Nobody had made any acknowledgment of Mr. Carton's part in the day's proceedings; nobody had known of it.", 'answer': 'nobody'}
{'question': 'When do the innocent Mr. Lorry hope you have been preserved for a prosperous and happy life?', 'source': 'I hope you have been this day preserved for a prosperous and happy life.', 'answer': 'this day'}
{'question': 'Who had Mr. Darnay turned to?', 'source': 'Mr. Darnay had kissed her hand fervently and gratefully, and had turned to Mr. Stryver, whom he warmly thanked.', 'answer': 'to Mr. Stryver'}
{'question': 'Who said bless the innocent Mr. Lorry, _ I _ have no business?', 'source': "Bless you, _ I _ have no business,'' said Mr. Carton.", 'answer': 'Mr. Carton'}
{'question': 'What had eke at the Sessions, Mr. Stryver charged to wake him?', 'source': "``Ten o'clock, sir,'' said the man at the tavern, whom he had charged to wake him-- ``ten o'clock, sir.''", 'answer': 'the tavern'}
{'question': 'What had begun cautiously to hew away the lower staves of the ladder on which he mounted?', 'source': 'A favorite at the Old Bailey, and eke at the Sessions, Mr. Stryver had begun cautiously to hew away the lower staves of the ladder on which he mounted.', 'answer': 'a favorite at the Old Bailey, and eke at the Sessions'}
{'question': 'What had eke at the Sessions, Mr. Stryver the tavern charged to him?', 'source': "``Ten o'clock, sir,'' said the man at the tavern, whom he had charged to wake him-- ``ten o'clock, sir.''", 'answer': 'to wake'}
{'question': 'Who was Sydney Carton idlest and most unpromising of?', 'source': "Sydney Carton, idlest and most unpromising of men, was Stryver's great ally.", 'answer': 'of men'}
{'question': 'Whose Bench-walk and Paper-buildings were turned into the Stryver chambers?', 'source': "He turned into the Temple, and, having revived himself by twice pacing the pavements of King's Bench-walk and Paper-buildings, turned into the Stryver chambers.", 'answer': "King's Bench-walk and Paper-buildings"}
{'question': 'Whose great ally was Sydney Carton?', 'source': "Sydney Carton, idlest and most unpromising of men, was Stryver's great ally.", 'answer': "Stryver's great ally"}
{'question': 'Who converted to Roman Catholicism in 1668 or 1669?', 'source': 'The Duke of York converted to Roman Catholicism in 1668 or 1669, but Mary and Anne had a Protestant upbringing, pursuant to the command of Charles II.', 'answer': 'the Duke of York'}
{'question': 'Where did the Duke of York convert in 1668 or 1669?', 'source': 'The Duke of York converted to Roman Catholicism in 1668 or 1669, but Mary and Anne had a Protestant upbringing, pursuant to the command of Charles II.', 'answer': 'to Roman Catholicism'}
{'question': "Whose uncle was Charles II served for a lengthy period as Charles's chief advisor?", 'source': "Mary's uncle was Charles II; her maternal grandfather, Edward Hyde, 1st Earl of Clarendon, served for a lengthy period as Charles's chief advisor.", 'answer': "Mary's uncle"}
{'question': "Who was Charles II served for a lengthy period as Charles's chief advisor?", 'source': "Mary's uncle was Charles II; her maternal grandfather, Edward Hyde, 1st Earl of Clarendon, served for a lengthy period as Charles's chief advisor.", 'answer': "Mary's uncle"}
{'question': 'Who had a Protestant upbringing, pursuant to the command of Charles II?', 'source': 'The Duke of York converted to Roman Catholicism in 1668 or 1669, but Mary and Anne had a Protestant upbringing, pursuant to the command of Charles II.', 'answer': 'Mary and Anne'}
{'question': "Who was Mary's uncle served for a lengthy period as Charles's chief advisor?", 'source': "Mary's uncle was Charles II; her maternal grandfather, Edward Hyde, 1st Earl of Clarendon, served for a lengthy period as Charles's chief advisor.", 'answer': 'Charles II'}
{'question': "Whose chief advisor was Mary's uncle Charles II served for a lengthy period as?", 'source': "Mary's uncle was Charles II; her maternal grandfather, Edward Hyde, 1st Earl of Clarendon, served for a lengthy period as Charles's chief advisor.", 'answer': "as Charles's chief advisor"}
{'question': "What resulted in the deposition of Mary's Roman Catholic father?", 'source': 'Mary, a Protestant, came to the thrones following the Glorious Revolution, which resulted in the deposition of her Roman Catholic father, James II and VII.', 'answer': 'the Glorious Revolution'}
{'question': "Who was Mary's uncle Charles II served for a lengthy period as?", 'source': "Mary's uncle was Charles II; her maternal grandfather, Edward Hyde, 1st Earl of Clarendon, served for a lengthy period as Charles's chief advisor.", 'answer': "as Charles's chief advisor"}
{'question': 'Where did the first cousins Mary and William marry on 4 November 1677?', 'source': 'The first cousins Mary and William married in London on 4 November 1677; Mary reportedly wept throughout the ceremony.', 'answer': 'in London'}
{'question': 'Who became betrothed to the Protestant Stadtholder Prince of Orange at the age of fifteen?', 'source': 'At the age of fifteen, Lady Mary became betrothed to the Protestant Stadtholder, William, Prince of Orange.', 'answer': 'Lady Mary'}
{'question': "When was Mary's uncle Charles II served as Charles's chief advisor?", 'source': "Mary's uncle was Charles II; her maternal grandfather, Edward Hyde, 1st Earl of Clarendon, served for a lengthy period as Charles's chief advisor.", 'answer': 'for a lengthy period'}
{'question': 'What did the Duke of York convert to in 1668 or 1669?', 'source': 'The Duke of York converted to Roman Catholicism in 1668 or 1669, but Mary and Anne had a Protestant upbringing, pursuant to the command of Charles II.', 'answer': 'to Roman Catholicism'}
{'question': 'Who married in London on 4 November 1677?', 'source': 'The first cousins Mary and William married in London on 4 November 1677; Mary reportedly wept throughout the ceremony.', 'answer': 'the first cousins Mary and William'}
{'question': "Who ruled England as less power's Supreme Governor?", 'source': 'She was very active in the Church of England, which she ruled as its Supreme Governor.', 'answer': 'Mary'}
{'question': 'When did the Duke of York convert to Roman Catholicism?', 'source': 'The Duke of York converted to Roman Catholicism in 1668 or 1669, but Mary and Anne had a Protestant upbringing, pursuant to the command of Charles II.', 'answer': 'in 1668 or 1669'}
{'question': 'Where was Mary born April 1662?', 'source': 'Mary, born at St. James Palace in London on 30 April 1662, was the eldest daughter of James, Duke of York (the future James II of England) and of his first wife, Lady Anne Hyde.', 'answer': 'at St. James Palace in London on 30'}
{'question': 'Who did Lady Mary become betrothed to at the age of fifteen?', 'source': 'At the age of fifteen, Lady Mary became betrothed to the Protestant Stadtholder, William, Prince of Orange.', 'answer': 'to the Protestant Stadtholder Prince of Orange'}
{'question': 'Whose Supreme Governor did Mary rule England as?', 'source': 'She was very active in the Church of England, which she ruled as its Supreme Governor.', 'answer': "as less power's Supreme Governor"}
{'question': 'What did William III and II become the sole ruler of both countries upon in 1694?', 'source': 'Mary reigned jointly with her husband and first cousin, William III and II, who became the sole ruler of both countries upon her death in 1694.', 'answer': "upon Mary's death"}
{'question': 'Who was the eldest daughter of James, Duke of York and, Lady Anne Hyde?', 'source': 'Mary, born at St. James Palace in London on 30 April 1662, was the eldest daughter of James, Duke of York (the future James II of England) and of his first wife, Lady Anne Hyde.', 'answer': 'Mary'}
{'question': "When did William III and II become the sole ruler of both countries upon Mary's death?", 'source': 'Mary reigned jointly with her husband and first cousin, William III and II, who became the sole ruler of both countries upon her death in 1694.', 'answer': 'in 1694'}
{'question': 'Who wielded less power than William during the parts of her reign when William remained in England?', 'source': 'Mary, the blood sovereign, wielded less power than William during the parts of her reign when William remained in England, ceding most of her authority to her husband, though he heavily relied on her.', 'answer': 'Mary'}
{'question': 'What did the first cousins Mary and William marry in on 4 November 1677?', 'source': 'The first cousins Mary and William married in London on 4 November 1677; Mary reportedly wept throughout the ceremony.', 'answer': 'in London'}
{'question': 'Who assumed that the marriage would improve his popularity amongst Protestants?', 'source': 'Pressured by Parliament, the Duke of York agreed to the marriage, falsely assuming that it would improve his popularity amongst Protestants.', 'answer': 'the Duke of York'}
{'question': 'Whose death did William III and II become the sole ruler of both countries upon in 1694?', 'source': 'Mary reigned jointly with her husband and first cousin, William III and II, who became the sole ruler of both countries upon her death in 1694.', 'answer': "upon Mary's death"}
{'question': 'When did the first cousins Mary and William marry in London on 4?', 'source': 'The first cousins Mary and William married in London on 4 November 1677; Mary reportedly wept throughout the ceremony.', 'answer': 'November 1677'}
{'question': "Whose chief advisor was Mary's uncle for?", 'source': "Mary's uncle was Charles II; her maternal grandfather, Edward Hyde, 1st Earl of Clarendon, served for a lengthy period as Charles's chief advisor.", 'answer': "Charles II served for a lengthy period as Charles's chief advisor"}
{'question': 'Who did Mary wield less power than during the parts of her reign when William remained in England?', 'source': 'Mary, the blood sovereign, wielded less power than William during the parts of her reign when William remained in England, ceding most of her authority to her husband, though he heavily relied on her.', 'answer': 'than William'}
{'question': "Who was also known as Mary Beatrice d' Este?", 'source': "Mary's mother died in 1671; her father remarried in 1673, taking as his second wife the Catholic Mary of Modena, also known as Mary Beatrice d' Este.", 'answer': 'Modena'}
{'question': 'Who came to the thrones following the Glorious Revolution, James II and VII?', 'source': 'Mary, a Protestant, came to the thrones following the Glorious Revolution, which resulted in the deposition of her Roman Catholic father, James II and VII.', 'answer': 'Mary'}
{'question': 'What did Mary and Anne have?', 'source': 'The Duke of York converted to Roman Catholicism in 1668 or 1669, but Mary and Anne had a Protestant upbringing, pursuant to the command of Charles II.', 'answer': 'a Protestant upbringing, pursuant to the command of Charles II'}
{'question': "What did Mary rule as less power's Supreme Governor?", 'source': 'She was very active in the Church of England, which she ruled as its Supreme Governor.', 'answer': 'England'}
{'question': 'Who did Mary rule England as?', 'source': 'She was very active in the Church of England, which she ruled as its Supreme Governor.', 'answer': "as less power's Supreme Governor"}
{'question': 'Who was very active in the Church of England?', 'source': 'She was very active in the Church of England, which she ruled as its Supreme Governor.', 'answer': 'Mary'}
{'question': 'Who did the Duke of York assume that the marriage would improve his popularity amongst?', 'source': 'Pressured by Parliament, the Duke of York agreed to the marriage, falsely assuming that it would improve his popularity amongst Protestants.', 'answer': 'amongst Protestants'}
{'question': "Who became the sole ruler of both countries upon Mary's death in 1694?", 'source': 'Mary reigned jointly with her husband and first cousin, William III and II, who became the sole ruler of both countries upon her death in 1694.', 'answer': 'William III and II'}
{'question': 'What was Mary born at April 1662?', 'source': 'Mary, born at St. James Palace in London on 30 April 1662, was the eldest daughter of James, Duke of York (the future James II of England) and of his first wife, Lady Anne Hyde.', 'answer': 'at St. James Palace in London on 30'}
{'question': 'What was the Duke of York pressured by?', 'source': 'Pressured by Parliament, the Duke of York agreed to the marriage, falsely assuming that it would improve his popularity amongst Protestants.', 'answer': 'by Parliament'}
{'question': 'What did the Glorious Revolution result in?', 'source': 'Mary, a Protestant, came to the thrones following the Glorious Revolution, which resulted in the deposition of her Roman Catholic father, James II and VII.', 'answer': "in the deposition of Mary's Roman Catholic father"}
{'question': 'What did Lady Mary become betrothed to the Protestant Stadtholder Prince of Orange at?', 'source': 'At the age of fifteen, Lady Mary became betrothed to the Protestant Stadtholder, William, Prince of Orange.', 'answer': 'at the age of fifteen'}
{'question': 'What did the Duke of York agree to?', 'source': 'Pressured by Parliament, the Duke of York agreed to the marriage, falsely assuming that it would improve his popularity amongst Protestants.', 'answer': 'to the marriage'}
{'question': 'Whose fidelity of belief in Solomon was quite a serious matter with Mr. Lorry?', 'source': "Miss Pross's fidelity of belief in Solomon (deducting a mere trifle for this slight mistake) was quite a serious matter with Mr. Lorry, and had its weight in his good opinion of her.", 'answer': "Miss Pross's fidelity of belief in Solomon"}
{'question': 'When was several callings purported to be pursued by day at the large stiff house, but whereof little audible?', 'source': 'The Doctor occupied two floors of a large stiff house, where several callings purported to be pursued by day, but whereof little was audible any day, and which was shunned by all of them at night.', 'answer': 'any day'}
{'question': "What was Miss Pross's fidelity of belief in Solomon quite?", 'source': "Miss Pross's fidelity of belief in Solomon (deducting a mere trifle for this slight mistake) was quite a serious matter with Mr. Lorry, and had its weight in his good opinion of her.", 'answer': 'a serious matter with Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'What was quite a serious matter with Mr. Lorry?', 'source': "Miss Pross's fidelity of belief in Solomon (deducting a mere trifle for this slight mistake) was quite a serious matter with Mr. Lorry, and had its weight in his good opinion of her.", 'answer': "Miss Pross's fidelity of belief in Solomon"}
{'question': 'Who had first made at the Royal George Hotel at Dover?', 'source': 'It proceeded from Miss Pross, the wild red woman, strong of hand, whose acquaintance he had first made at the Royal George Hotel at Dover, and had since improved.', 'answer': 'Miss Pross'}
{'question': "Who struck in ``There is a great crowd coming one day into such whims's lives''?", 'source': "``There is a great crowd coming one day into our lives, if that be so,'' Sydney Carton struck in, in his moody way.", 'answer': 'Sydney Carton'}
{'question': 'What had Miss Pross first made at at Dover?', 'source': 'It proceeded from Miss Pross, the wild red woman, strong of hand, whose acquaintance he had first made at the Royal George Hotel at Dover, and had since improved.', 'answer': 'at the Royal George Hotel'}
{'question': "Who did Miss Pross say ``do not want dozens of people who are not at all worthy of Ladybird''?", 'source': "``I do not want dozens of people who are not at all worthy of Ladybird, to come here looking after her,'' said Miss Pross.", 'answer': 'Doctor Manette'}
{'question': "Who said ``Doctor Manette do not want dozens of people who are not at all worthy of Ladybird''?", 'source': "``I do not want dozens of people who are not at all worthy of Ladybird, to come here looking after her,'' said Miss Pross.", 'answer': 'Miss Pross'}
{'question': "What came to see the sights, and Mr. Lorry looked in vain for the fulfilment of Miss Pross's prediction?", 'source': "But, no Hundreds of people came to see the sights, and Mr. Lorry looked in vain for the fulfilment of Miss Pross's prediction.", 'answer': 'no Hundreds of people'}
{'question': 'Who walked towards Soho?', 'source': 'On this certain fine Sunday, Mr. Lorry walked towards Soho, early in the afternoon, for three reasons of habit.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': "When said Mr. Lorry, ``to bring the dead out of their graves?''", 'source': "Almost a night, Jerry,'' said Mr. Lorry, ``to bring the dead out of their graves.''", 'answer': 'a night'}
{'question': "What was the sunny part of Mr. Lorry's life?", 'source': "After several relapses into business-absorption, Mr. Lorry had become the Doctor's friend, and the quiet street-corner was the sunny part of his life.", 'answer': 'the quiet street-corner'}
{'question': "What were within Mr. Jarvis Lorry's knowledge, thoughts, and notice?", 'source': "These things were within Mr. Jarvis Lorry's knowledge, thoughts, and notice, when he rang the door-bell of the tranquil house in the corner, on the fine Sunday afternoon.", 'answer': 'these things'}
{'question': 'What could roar of rain that Mr. Carton typified be heard in?', 'source': 'It was the rush and roar of rain that he typified, and it stopped him, for no voice could be heard in it.', 'answer': 'in a peal of thunder'}
{'question': 'What were the quiet lodgings of Doctor Manette in street-corner not far from Soho-square?', 'source': 'The quiet lodgings of Doctor Manette were in a quiet street-corner not far from Soho-square.', 'answer': 'in a quiet'}
{'question': 'What were in a quiet street-corner not far from Soho-square?', 'source': 'The quiet lodgings of Doctor Manette were in a quiet street-corner not far from Soho-square.', 'answer': 'the quiet lodgings of Doctor Manette'}
{'question': 'Where had Miss Pross first made at the Royal George Hotel?', 'source': 'It proceeded from Miss Pross, the wild red woman, strong of hand, whose acquaintance he had first made at the Royal George Hotel at Dover, and had since improved.', 'answer': 'at Dover'}
{'question': 'Who proposed that the wine should be carried out under the plane-tree after dinner?', 'source': 'It was an oppressive day, and, after dinner, Lucie proposed that the wine should be carried out under the plane-tree, and they should sit there in the air.', 'answer': 'Lucie'}
{'question': 'Who said and Mr. Lorry left off?', 'source': 'said Miss Pross; and Mr. Lorry left off.', 'answer': 'Miss Pross'}
{'question': "Who was with meekness; ``how are Doctor Manette?''?", 'source': "``I am pretty well, I thank you,'' answered Mr. Lorry, with meekness; ``how are you?''", 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Who called Mr. Jarvis Lorry?', 'source': 'The blue-flies buzzed again, and Mr. Attorney-General called Mr. Jarvis Lorry.', 'answer': 'Mr. Attorney-General'}
{'question': 'Who touched Mr. Lorry on the arm?', 'source': 'Mr. Carton came up at the moment, and touched Mr. Lorry on the arm.', 'answer': 'Mr. Carton'}
{'question': 'Who did Mr. Carton touch on the arm?', 'source': 'Mr. Carton came up at the moment, and touched Mr. Lorry on the arm.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': "Who reddened as if he were conscious of having debated the point in Mr. Carton's mind?", 'source': 'Mr. Lorry reddened as if he were conscious of having debated the point in his mind, and Mr. Carton made his way to the outside of the bar.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Carton touch Mr. Lorry on?', 'source': 'Mr. Carton came up at the moment, and touched Mr. Lorry on the arm.', 'answer': 'on the arm'}
{'question': 'Who Solicitor-General then examined the patriot: John Barsad by name?', 'source': "Mr. Solicitor-General then, following his leader's lead, examined the patriot: John Barsad, gentleman, by name.", 'answer': 'Mr.'}
{'question': 'Who reddened as if Mr. Carton made his way to the outside of the bar?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry reddened as if he were conscious of having debated the point in his mind, and Mr. Carton made his way to the outside of the bar.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': "Who fell downstairs of Mr.'s own accord?", 'source': 'Decidedly not; once received a kick on the top of a staircase, and fell downstairs of his own accord.', 'answer': 'Decidedly'}
{'question': 'Whose hurried right hand parcelled out the herbs before him into imaginary beds of flowers in a garden?', 'source': 'His hurried right hand parcelled out the herbs before him into imaginary beds of flowers in a garden; and his efforts to control and steady his breathing shook the lips from which the color rushed to his heart.', 'answer': "Miss Manette's hurried right hand"}
{'question': 'Who did Mr. Attorney-General call?', 'source': 'The blue-flies buzzed again, and Mr. Attorney-General called Mr. Jarvis Lorry.', 'answer': 'Mr. Jarvis Lorry'}
{'question': 'Who inquired of Mr. Stryver for treason?', 'source': "My Lord inquired of Mr. Stryver (the prisoner's counsel), whether they were next to try Mr. Carton (name of my learned friend) for treason?", 'answer': 'my Lord'}
{'question': "Who muttered ``If Mr. Lorry had sent the message, ` Recalled to Life''?", 'source': "``If you had sent the message, ` Recalled to Life, ' again,'' muttered Jerry, as he turned, ``I should have known what you meant, this time.''", 'answer': 'Jerry'}
{'question': 'Who was of Beauvais like Monsieur Manette?', 'source': 'Like Monsieur Manette, your father, the gentleman was of Beauvais.', 'answer': 'the gentleman'}
{'question': 'Who was of repute in Paris like Monsieur Manette?', 'source': 'Like Monsieur Manette, your father, the gentleman was of repute in Paris.', 'answer': 'the gentleman'}
{'question': 'Who cast a troubled look towards the hospital procession of negro cupids?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry moved in his chair, and cast a troubled look towards the hospital procession of negro cupids.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Who was the gentleman of like Monsieur Manette?', 'source': 'Like Monsieur Manette, your father, the gentleman was of Beauvais.', 'answer': 'of Beauvais'}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Lorry extend outwards with an argumentative smile?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry opened his hands, and extended them outwards with an argumentative smile.', 'answer': 'other hands'}
{'question': 'Who extended other hands outwards with an argumentative smile?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry opened his hands, and extended them outwards with an argumentative smile.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'What was the gentleman of like Monsieur Manette?', 'source': 'Like Monsieur Manette, your father, the gentleman was of repute in Paris.', 'answer': 'of repute in Paris'}
{'question': 'Who has been taken to the house of an old servant in Paris?', 'source': "Your father has been taken to the house of an old servant in Paris, and we are going there: I, to identify him if I can: you, to restore him to life, love, duty, rest, comfort.''", 'answer': "the composed and reserved expression of Tellson's Bank's father"}
{'question': "What has the composed and reserved expression of Tellson's Bank's father been taken to?", 'source': "Your father has been taken to the house of an old servant in Paris, and we are going there: I, to identify him if I can: you, to restore him to life, love, duty, rest, comfort.''", 'answer': 'to the house of an old servant in Paris'}
{'question': 'Who did the head drawer at the Royal George Hotel open as his custom was?', 'source': 'When the mail got successfully to Dover, in the course of the forenoon, the head drawer at the Royal George Hotel opened the coach-door as his custom was.', 'answer': 'the coach-door'}
{'question': "Where does Gentleman's valise and hot water?", 'source': "Gentleman's valise and hot water to Concord.", 'answer': 'to Concord'}
{'question': 'Who was the gentleman of repute in Paris like?', 'source': 'Like Monsieur Manette, your father, the gentleman was of repute in Paris.', 'answer': 'like Monsieur Manette'}
{'question': "When did the waiter come in to announce that Miss Manette had arrived from London, and would be happy to see the gentleman from Tellson's?", 'source': "In a very few minutes the waiter came in to announce that Miss Manette had arrived from London, and would be happy to see the gentleman from Tellson's.", 'answer': 'in a very few minutes'}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Lorry cast?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry moved in his chair, and cast a troubled look towards the hospital procession of negro cupids.', 'answer': 'a troubled look towards the hospital procession of negro cupids'}
{'question': 'Who was the gentleman of Beauvais like?', 'source': 'Like Monsieur Manette, your father, the gentleman was of Beauvais.', 'answer': 'like Monsieur Manette'}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Lorry extend other hands outwards with?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry opened his hands, and extended them outwards with an argumentative smile.', 'answer': 'with an argumentative smile'}
{'question': 'Who were principally occupied with the cares of other people?', 'source': "But, perhaps the confidential bachelor clerks in Tellson's Bank were principally occupied with the cares of other people; and perhaps second-hand cares, like second-hand clothes, come easily off and on.", 'answer': "the confidential bachelor clerks in Tellson's Bank"}
{'question': 'Who was appointed Abbot of Tavistock Abbey in around 1027?', 'source': 'After becoming a monk at the monastery at Winchester, he was appointed Abbot of Tavistock Abbey in around 1027.', 'answer': 'Ealdred'}
{'question': 'Who was Ealdred in Anglo-Saxon England?', 'source': 'Ealdred was Abbot of Tavistock, Bishop of Worcester, and Archbishop of York in Anglo-Saxon England.', 'answer': 'Abbot of Tavistock, Bishop of Worcester, and Archbishop of York'}
{'question': 'Where was Ealdred Abbot of Tavistock, Bishop of Worcester, and Archbishop of York?', 'source': 'Ealdred was Abbot of Tavistock, Bishop of Worcester, and Archbishop of York in Anglo-Saxon England.', 'answer': 'in Anglo-Saxon England'}
{'question': 'What was Ealdred appointed Abbot of Tavistock Abbey in?', 'source': 'After becoming a monk at the monastery at Winchester, he was appointed Abbot of Tavistock Abbey in around 1027.', 'answer': 'in around 1027'}
{'question': 'Who was Ealdred Abbot of of York in Anglo-Saxon England?', 'source': 'Ealdred was Abbot of Tavistock, Bishop of Worcester, and Archbishop of York in Anglo-Saxon England.', 'answer': 'of Tavistock, Bishop of Worcester, and Archbishop'}
{'question': 'What was Ealdred appointed Abbot of in around 1027?', 'source': 'After becoming a monk at the monastery at Winchester, he was appointed Abbot of Tavistock Abbey in around 1027.', 'answer': 'of Tavistock Abbey'}
{'question': 'When was Ealdred named to the Bishopric of Worcester?', 'source': 'In 1046 he was named to the Bishopric of Worcester.', 'answer': 'in 1046'}
{'question': 'Who was Ealdred appointed in around 1027?', 'source': 'After becoming a monk at the monastery at Winchester, he was appointed Abbot of Tavistock Abbey in around 1027.', 'answer': 'Abbot of Tavistock Abbey'}
{'question': 'Who was Abbot of Tavistock, Bishop of Worcester, and Archbishop of York in Anglo-Saxon England?', 'source': 'Ealdred was Abbot of Tavistock, Bishop of Worcester, and Archbishop of York in Anglo-Saxon England.', 'answer': 'Ealdred'}
{'question': 'Who served Edward the Confessor as a diplomat and as a military leader?', 'source': 'Ealdred, besides his episcopal duties, served Edward the Confessor, the King of England, as a diplomat and as a military leader.', 'answer': 'Ealdred'}
{'question': 'Who was named to the Bishopric of Worcester in 1046?', 'source': 'In 1046 he was named to the Bishopric of Worcester.', 'answer': 'Ealdred'}
{'question': "Where did Ealdred work to bring one of the king's relatives back from Hungary to secure an heir for the childless king?", 'source': "He worked to bring one of the king's relatives, Edward the Exile, back to England from Hungary to secure an heir for the childless king.", 'answer': 'to England'}
{'question': 'Where was Ealdred named in 1046?', 'source': 'In 1046 he was named to the Bishopric of Worcester.', 'answer': 'to the Bishopric of Worcester'}
{'question': 'What was Ealdred Abbot of Tavistock, Bishop of Worcester, and Archbishop of York in?', 'source': 'Ealdred was Abbot of Tavistock, Bishop of Worcester, and Archbishop of York in Anglo-Saxon England.', 'answer': 'in Anglo-Saxon England'}
{'question': 'Who presented where breathless to Monsieur the Marquis?', 'source': 'Some half-dozen other particular friends promptly hauled him out, and presented him breathless to Monsieur the Marquis.', 'answer': 'some half-dozen other particular friends'}
{'question': 'What did High vault rooms with cool uncarpeted floors upon in a luxurious age and country?', 'source': 'High vaulted rooms with cool uncarpeted floors, great dogs upon the hearths for the burning of wood in winter time, and all luxuries befitting the state of a marquis in a luxurious age and country.', 'answer': 'upon the hearths for the burning of wood in winter time, and all luxuries befitting the state of a marquis'}
{'question': 'What lay back on the pillow of Monsieur the Marquis?', 'source': 'It lay back on the pillow of Monsieur the Marquis.', 'answer': 'the midst of a group of fifty particular friends'}
{'question': 'What was diversified by many objects that were illustrations of old pages in the history of France?', 'source': 'The fashion of the last Louis but one, of the line that was never to break-- the fourteenth Louis-- was conspicuous in their rich furniture; but, it was diversified by many objects that were illustrations of old pages in the history of France.', 'answer': 'the fashion of the last Louis but one, of the line that was never to break-- the fourteenth Louis--'}
{'question': 'Who had been known in England as Charles Darnay?', 'source': 'He had been known in England as Charles Darnay.', 'answer': 'the imperturbable master'}
{'question': 'Where had the imperturbable master been known as Charles Darnay?', 'source': 'He had been known in England as Charles Darnay.', 'answer': 'in England'}
{'question': 'What did Monsieur the Marquis disturb the darkness to elicit loud remonstrance from away among the trees?', 'source': 'Up the broad flight of shallow steps, Monsieur the Marquis, flambeau preceded, went from his carriage, sufficiently disturbing the darkness to elicit loud remonstrance from an owl in the roof of the great pile of stable building away among the trees.', 'answer': 'from an owl in the roof of the great pile of stable building'}
{'question': 'Who went up the staircase to a door in a corridor avoiding the larger rooms?', 'source': 'Avoiding the larger rooms, which were dark and made fast for the night, Monsieur the Marquis, with his flambeau-bearer going on before, went up the staircase to a door in a corridor.', 'answer': 'Monsieur the Marquis'}
{'question': "Where did dead darkness add all the landscape's own hush to the hushing dust on all the roads Dead darkness lay?", 'source': 'Dead darkness lay on all the landscape, dead darkness added its own hush to the hushing dust on all the roads.', 'answer': 'on all the landscape'}
{'question': 'What curved with a sarcasm that looked handsomely diabolic at the same time?', 'source': 'At the same time, the thin straight lines of the setting of the eyes, and the thin straight lips, and the markings in the nose, curved with a sarcasm that looked handsomely diabolic.', 'answer': 'the thin straight lines of the setting of the eyes'}
{'question': 'Who had the imperturbable master been known in England as?', 'source': 'He had been known in England as Charles Darnay.', 'answer': 'as Charles Darnay'}
{'question': 'What had the imperturbable master been known in as Charles Darnay?', 'source': 'He had been known in England as Charles Darnay.', 'answer': 'in England'}
{'question': 'What did Monsieur the Marquis go up the staircase to a door in a corridor?', 'source': 'Avoiding the larger rooms, which were dark and made fast for the night, Monsieur the Marquis, with his flambeau-bearer going on before, went up the staircase to a door in a corridor.', 'answer': 'avoiding the larger rooms'}
{'question': 'What did dead darkness add to the hushing dust on all the roads Dead darkness lay on all the landscape?', 'source': 'Dead darkness lay on all the landscape, dead darkness added its own hush to the hushing dust on all the roads.', 'answer': "all the landscape's own hush"}
{'question': "What added all the landscape's own hush to the hushing dust on all the roads Dead darkness lay on all the landscape?", 'source': 'Dead darkness lay on all the landscape, dead darkness added its own hush to the hushing dust on all the roads.', 'answer': 'dead darkness'}
{'question': 'What did Monsieur the Marquis go up the staircase to in a corridor avoiding the larger rooms?', 'source': 'Avoiding the larger rooms, which were dark and made fast for the night, Monsieur the Marquis, with his flambeau-bearer going on before, went up the staircase to a door in a corridor.', 'answer': 'to a door'}
{'question': 'What did Monsieur the Marquis go up to a door in a corridor avoiding the larger rooms?', 'source': 'Avoiding the larger rooms, which were dark and made fast for the night, Monsieur the Marquis, with his flambeau-bearer going on before, went up the staircase to a door in a corridor.', 'answer': 'the staircase'}
{'question': "Who did Monsieur Defarge say ``have a visitor''?", 'source': "``You have a visitor, you see,'' said Monsieur Defarge.", 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Who knows a well-made shoe when Monsieur Defarge sees one?', 'source': '``Here is monsieur, who knows a well-made shoe when he sees one.', 'answer': 'monsieur'}
{'question': "Who said ``Mr. Lorry have a visitor''?", 'source': "``You have a visitor, you see,'' said Monsieur Defarge.", 'answer': 'Monsieur Defarge'}
{'question': 'What was Madame Defarge-- who leaned against the door-post, knitting?', 'source': 'Only one soul was to be seen, and that was Madame Defarge-- who leaned against the door-post, knitting, and saw nothing.', 'answer': 'that'}
{'question': 'What evidently was for the strong fortress-walls which had long encompassed Monsieur Defarge?', 'source': "They heard him mutter, ``One Hundred and Five, North Tower;'' and when he looked about him, it evidently was for the strong fortress-walls which had long encompassed him.", 'answer': 'North Tower'}
{'question': 'Who glanced at the shoe with some little passing touch of pride?', 'source': 'He glanced at the shoe with some little passing touch of pride.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': "What could have read the mysteries of Monsieur Defarge's mind?", 'source': 'No human intelligence could have read the mysteries of his mind, in the scared blank wonder of his face.', 'answer': 'no human intelligence'}
{'question': "Who gave the word ``To the Barrier!''", 'source': "Defarge got upon the box, and gave the word ``To the Barrier!''", 'answer': 'Defarge'}
{'question': 'Who recollected what Mr. Lorry had said to him?', 'source': 'Whether he knew what had happened, whether he recollected what they had said to him, whether he knew that he was free, were questions which no sagacity could have solved.', 'answer': 'Monsieur Defarge'}
{'question': 'When did Mr. Lorry get the face with much difficulty?', 'source': "``I asked leave to teach myself, and I got it with much difficulty after a long while, and I have made shoes ever since.''", 'answer': 'after a long while'}
{'question': "Who did Monsieur Defarge say ``Mr. Lorry have''?", 'source': "``You have a visitor, you see,'' said Monsieur Defarge.", 'answer': 'a visitor'}
{'question': 'What was one of the first considerations which arose in the business mind of Mr. Lorry when business hours came round, ?', 'source': "One of the first considerations which arose in the business mind of Mr. Lorry when business hours came round, was this:-- that he had no right to imperil Tellson's by sheltering the wife of an emigrant prisoner under the Bank roof.", 'answer': "this:-- that he had no right to imperil Tellson's by sheltering the wife of an emigrant prisoner under the Bank roof"}
{'question': "Who said: ``You come from Doctor Manette?''", 'source': "Much interested and agitated, Mr. Lorry said: ``You come from Doctor Manette?''", 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Who have obtained the favor that the bearer has a short note from Charles to his wife?', 'source': 'I have obtained the favor that the bearer has a short note from Charles to his wife.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Who met the lifted eyebrows and forehead with a cold, impassive stare?', 'source': 'Madame Defarge met the lifted eyebrows and forehead with a cold, impassive stare.', 'answer': 'Madame Defarge'}
{'question': "Who did Mr. Lorry say: ``You come from?''", 'source': "Much interested and agitated, Mr. Lorry said: ``You come from Doctor Manette?''", 'answer': 'from Doctor Manette'}
{'question': 'Who advised with Lucie?', 'source': "Noon coming, and the Doctor not returning, and every minute's delay tending to compromise Tellson's, Mr. Lorry advised with Lucie.", 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': "Who began to be struck by Defarge's manner?", 'source': "Beginning to be struck by Defarge's manner, Mr. Lorry looked dubiously at him, and led the way.", 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Who did the business mind of Mr. Lorry wear out with it?', 'source': 'It wore itself out, and wore him out with it, until the Bank closed.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Who have Mr. Lorry obtained the favor that the bearer has a short note from to his wife?', 'source': 'I have obtained the favor that the bearer has a short note from Charles to his wife.', 'answer': 'from Charles'}
{'question': 'What did Madame Defarge meet with a cold, impassive stare?', 'source': 'Madame Defarge met the lifted eyebrows and forehead with a cold, impassive stare.', 'answer': 'the lifted eyebrows and forehead'}
{'question': 'What did Madame Defarge meet the lifted eyebrows and forehead with?', 'source': 'Madame Defarge met the lifted eyebrows and forehead with a cold, impassive stare.', 'answer': 'with a cold, impassive stare'}
{'question': 'Whose own occupations did Mr. Lorry retain to?', 'source': 'He left Jerry with them, as a figure to fill a doorway that would bear considerable knocking on the head, and retained to his own occupations.', 'answer': "to Jerry's own occupations"}
{'question': 'Whose manner did Mr. Lorry begin to be struck by?', 'source': "Beginning to be struck by Defarge's manner, Mr. Lorry looked dubiously at him, and led the way.", 'answer': "by Defarge's manner"}
{'question': 'Who gave no other answer than a gruff sound of acquiescence?', 'source': 'Defarge looked gloomily at his wife, and gave no other answer than a gruff sound of acquiescence.', 'answer': 'Defarge'}
{'question': 'Who did Mr. Lorry advise with?', 'source': "Noon coming, and the Doctor not returning, and every minute's delay tending to compromise Tellson's, Mr. Lorry advised with Lucie.", 'answer': 'with Lucie'}
{'question': 'What wore Mr. Lorry out with it?', 'source': 'It wore itself out, and wore him out with it, until the Bank closed.', 'answer': 'the business mind of Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': "Who must know Tellson's Bank in London?", 'source': "You must know Tellson's Bank in London.", 'answer': 'the passenger'}
{'question': "Who read ` Wait at Dover for Mam ` selle? '", 'source': "He opened it in the light of the coach-lamp on that side, and read-- first to himself and then aloud:'' ` Wait at Dover for Mam ` selle. '", 'answer': 'the passenger'}
{'question': 'Whose Hill did the Dover mail lumber up?', 'source': "The Dover road lay, as to him, beyond the Dover mail, as it lumbered up Shooter's Hill.", 'answer': "Shooter's Hill"}
{'question': 'Whose Bank in London must the passenger know?', 'source': "You must know Tellson's Bank in London.", 'answer': "Tellson's Bank in London"}
{'question': "Who tore away the gates of God's own Temple?", 'source': "The name of the strong man of Old Scripture had descended to the chief functionary who worked it; but, so armed, he was stronger than his namesake, and blinder, and tore away the gates of God's own Temple every day.", 'answer': 'the man sitting as President'}
{'question': 'Who had then informed Doctor Manette that the prisoner must remain in custody?', 'source': 'That, the man sitting as President had then informed Doctor Manette that the prisoner must remain in custody, but should, for his sake, be held inviolate in safe custody.', 'answer': 'the man sitting as President'}
{'question': 'Whose own Temple did the man sitting as President tear away the gates of?', 'source': "The name of the strong man of Old Scripture had descended to the chief functionary who worked it; but, so armed, he was stronger than his namesake, and blinder, and tore away the gates of God's own Temple every day.", 'answer': "of God's own Temple"}
{'question': 'What arose within Mr. Lorry that such dread experiences would revive the old danger?', 'source': 'As Mr. Lorry received these confidences, and as he watched the face of his friend now sixty-two years of age, a misgiving arose within him that such dread experiences would revive the old danger.', 'answer': 'a misgiving'}
{'question': 'Who did a misgiving arise within that such dread experiences would revive the old danger?', 'source': 'As Mr. Lorry received these confidences, and as he watched the face of his friend now sixty-two years of age, a misgiving arose within him that such dread experiences would revive the old danger.', 'answer': 'within Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Who had the man sitting as President then informed that the prisoner must remain in custody?', 'source': 'That, the man sitting as President had then informed Doctor Manette that the prisoner must remain in custody, but should, for his sake, be held inviolate in safe custody.', 'answer': 'Doctor Manette'}
{'question': 'What did a misgiving arise within Mr. Lorry that such dread experiences would revive?', 'source': 'As Mr. Lorry received these confidences, and as he watched the face of his friend now sixty-two years of age, a misgiving arose within him that such dread experiences would revive the old danger.', 'answer': 'the old danger'}
{'question': 'What had the man sitting as President then informed Doctor Manette that the prisoner must remain in?', 'source': 'That, the man sitting as President had then informed Doctor Manette that the prisoner must remain in custody, but should, for his sake, be held inviolate in safe custody.', 'answer': 'in custody'}
{'question': 'What were worn on breasts from which the Cross was discarded?', 'source': 'Models of it were worn on breasts from which the Cross was discarded, and it was bowed down to and believed in where the Cross was denied.', 'answer': 'models of one hideous figure'}
{'question': 'What did the man sitting as President tear away the gates of?', 'source': "The name of the strong man of Old Scripture had descended to the chief functionary who worked it; but, so armed, he was stronger than his namesake, and blinder, and tore away the gates of God's own Temple every day.", 'answer': "of God's own Temple"}
{'question': 'What was almost dark when a rising mist from the Seine arrived at the Bank?', 'source': 'It was almost dark when they arrived at the Bank.', 'answer': 'the approach of darkness'}
{'question': 'Who call myself the Samson of the firewood guillotine?', 'source': '``I call myself the Samson of the firewood guillotine.', 'answer': 'a cutter of wood into lengths for burning'}
{'question': 'What did a murky red and yellow sky, and a rising mist from the Seine, denote?', 'source': 'A murky red and yellow sky, and a rising mist from the Seine, denoted the approach of darkness.', 'answer': 'the approach of darkness'}
{'question': 'Whose return to France was the nothing that the decree bore date since?', 'source': 'It was nothing that the decree bore date since his return to France.', 'answer': "since Charles Evremonde's return to France"}
{'question': 'Who is only daughter of Doctor Manette?', 'source': "``Lucie Manette, only daughter of Doctor Manette, the good physician who sits there.''", 'answer': 'Lucie Manette'}
{'question': "When was the nothing that the decree bore since Charles Evremonde's return to France?", 'source': 'It was nothing that the decree bore date since his return to France.', 'answer': 'date'}
{'question': "What was nothing that the decree bore date since Charles Evremonde's return to France?", 'source': 'It was nothing that the decree bore date since his return to France.', 'answer': 'the'}
{'question': "Who were put to the bar before Charles Darnay's name was called?", 'source': "Next day, fifteen prisoners were put to the bar before Charles Darnay's name was called.", 'answer': 'fifteen prisoners'}
{'question': 'Who is Lucie Manette only daughter of?', 'source': "``Lucie Manette, only daughter of Doctor Manette, the good physician who sits there.''", 'answer': 'of Doctor Manette'}
{'question': 'When did the dread tribunal of five Judges, Public Prosecutor, and determined Jury, sit?', 'source': 'The dread tribunal of five Judges, Public Prosecutor, and determined Jury, sat every day.', 'answer': 'every day'}
{'question': 'Who was Charles Evremonde accused by as an emigrant?', 'source': 'Charles Evremonde, called Darnay, was accused by the public prosecutor as an emigrant, whose life was forfeit to the Republic, under the decree which banished all emigrants on pain of Death.', 'answer': 'by the public prosecutor'}
{'question': 'Who handed in the names of two witnesses; Theophile Gabelle, and Alexandre Manette?', 'source': 'He handed in the names of two witnesses; Theophile Gabelle, and Alexandre Manette.', 'answer': 'President'}
{'question': 'Who was Charles Evremonde accused by the public prosecutor as?', 'source': 'Charles Evremonde, called Darnay, was accused by the public prosecutor as an emigrant, whose life was forfeit to the Republic, under the decree which banished all emigrants on pain of Death.', 'answer': 'as an emigrant'}
{'question': 'Who sat upon the Bench in feathered hats?', 'source': 'His judges sat upon the Bench in feathered hats; but the rough red cap and tricoloured cockade was the head-dress otherwise prevailing.', 'answer': "Charles Evremonde's judges"}
{'question': "What was the that the decree bore date since Charles Evremonde's return to France?", 'source': 'It was nothing that the decree bore date since his return to France.', 'answer': 'nothing'}
{'question': 'Who sat Doctor Manette?', 'source': 'Under the President sat Doctor Manette, in his usual quiet dress.', 'answer': 'President'}
{'question': 'Whose judges sat upon the Bench in feathered hats?', 'source': 'His judges sat upon the Bench in feathered hats; but the rough red cap and tricoloured cockade was the head-dress otherwise prevailing.', 'answer': "Charles Evremonde's judges"}
{'question': 'Who was accused by the public prosecutor as an emigrant?', 'source': 'Charles Evremonde, called Darnay, was accused by the public prosecutor as an emigrant, whose life was forfeit to the Republic, under the decree which banished all emigrants on pain of Death.', 'answer': 'Charles Evremonde'}
{'question': "What were fifteen prisoners put to before Charles Darnay's name was called?", 'source': "Next day, fifteen prisoners were put to the bar before Charles Darnay's name was called.", 'answer': 'to the bar'}
{'question': 'Where had Charles Evremonde been taken?', 'source': 'There he was, and there was the decree; he had been taken in France, and his head was demanded.', 'answer': 'in France'}
{'question': 'Whose bloated gaoler wore spectacles to read with?', 'source': 'His bloated gaoler, who wore spectacles to read with, glanced over them to assure himself that he had taken his place, and went through the list, making a similar short pause at each name.', 'answer': "Charles Evremonde's bloated gaoler"}
{'question': "Where had the citizen's letter been taken from President?", 'source': "He also referred with confidence to the citizen's letter, which had been taken from him at the Barrier, but which he did not doubt would be found among the papers then before the President.", 'answer': 'at the Barrier'}
{'question': 'What had been taken from President at the Barrier?', 'source': "He also referred with confidence to the citizen's letter, which had been taken from him at the Barrier, but which he did not doubt would be found among the papers then before the President.", 'answer': "the citizen's letter"}
{'question': 'What were the society of La Force engaged in?', 'source': 'It was the incident of every day, and the society of La Force were engaged in the preparation of some games of forfeits and a little concert, for that evening.', 'answer': 'in the preparation'}
{'question': 'Who was in the courtyard when Mr. Lorry regained the blind?', 'source': 'Doctor Manette pressed his hand, hastened bareheaded out of the room, and was in the courtyard when Mr. Lorry regained the blind.', 'answer': 'Doctor Manette'}
{'question': 'What was established in the Saint Germain Quarter of Paris?', 'source': "Tellson's Bank, established in the Saint Germain Quarter of Paris, was in a wing of a large house, approached by a courtyard and shut off from the street by a high wall and a strong gate.", 'answer': "Tellson's Bank"}
{'question': 'Whose Bank was established in the Saint Germain Quarter of Paris?', 'source': "Tellson's Bank, established in the Saint Germain Quarter of Paris, was in a wing of a large house, approached by a courtyard and shut off from the street by a high wall and a strong gate.", 'answer': "Tellson's Bank"}
{'question': 'What was Doctor Manette in when Mr. Lorry regained the blind?', 'source': 'Doctor Manette pressed his hand, hastened bareheaded out of the room, and was in the courtyard when Mr. Lorry regained the blind.', 'answer': 'in the courtyard'}
{'question': 'Whose Bank was in a wing of a large house?', 'source': "Tellson's Bank, established in the Saint Germain Quarter of Paris, was in a wing of a large house, approached by a courtyard and shut off from the street by a high wall and a strong gate.", 'answer': "Tellson's Bank"}
{'question': 'Who was looking about Mr. Lorry with a vacant air?', 'source': 'A man, so besmeared that he might have been a sorely wounded soldier creeping back to consciousness on a field of slain, was rising from the pavement by the side of the grindstone, and looking about him with a vacant air.', 'answer': 'a man'}
{'question': 'What would soon have driven the House out of its mind and into the Gazette?', 'source': "A place of business in London like Tellson's place of business in Paris, would soon have driven the House out of its mind and into the Gazette.", 'answer': "a place of business in London like Tellson's place of business in Paris,"}
